Karl M. Waage Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Maps, Series I
  - Wyoming., 001208
    - Topographic map. Storm Hill, WY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. [Volume=Preliminary Edition], 1954; 002181
    - Topographic map. Devils Tower 1 SE, WY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. [Volume=Advance Proof], 1954; 002183
    - Topographic map. Aladdin 2 SW, WY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. [Volume=Advance Proof], 1954; 002184
    - Topographic map. Aladdin 3 NE, WY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic. [Volume=Advance Proof], 1954; 002185
    - Topographic map. Mule Creek, WY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1978; 001937
    - Topographic map. Funny Rock, WY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1981; 001936
    - Topographic map. Rabbit Mountains, WY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1981; 001939
    - Topographic map. Redbird, WY 7.5 Quad. (1: 24000). U.S. Geological Survey: Topographic., 1981; 001940
- Field Notebooks, 1938-1983; Series II
  - 1938-1950., 001211
    - Field notes. Field notebook for Fox Hills Fm, Lance Creek area, senior thesis for Princeton University: Wyoming., 1938; 000340
    - Field notes. Field notebook for Fox Hills Fm, Lance Creek area, senior thesis for Princeton University: Wyoming., 1938; 000341
    - Field notes. Field notebook for Fox Hills Fm, Lance Creek area, senior thesis for Princeton University: Wyoming., 1938; 000342
    - Field notes. Locality information in K.M. Waage Princeton senior thesis, and Erling Dorf Lance Fm publication: Wyoming., 1938; 000343
    - Locality information. Field notebook #1: Maryland (Castleman Basin - Georges Basin). 1945-1948, 000511
    - Notebook. Field notebook, type Fox Hills Fm: South Dakota., 1940; 000287
    - Notebook. Field notebook: South Dakota, North Dakota., 1941; 000288
    - Notebook. Field notebook #2: Maryland (Castleman Basin - Georges Basin). 1945-1948, 000512
    - Notebook. Field notebook #1: Maryland (Castleman Basin - Georges Basin). 1945-1948, 000513
    - Notebook. Field notebook #2: Maryland (Castleman Basin - Georges Basin). 1945-1948, 000514
    - Notebook. Field notebook #3: Maryland (Castleman Basin - Georges Basin). 1945-1948, 000515
    - Notebook. Field notebook: Maryland (Castleman Basin - Georges Basin). 1945-1948, 000516
    - Notebook. Field notebook: Maryland (Castleman Basin - Georges Basin). 1945-1948, 000517
    - Notebook. Field notebook: Maryland (Castleman Basin - Georges Basin). 1945-1948, 000518
    - Notebook. Field notebook: and maps, sections, and letters; Maryland (Castleman Basin - Georges Basin). 1945-1948, 000519
    - Notebook. Field notes: Utah., 1947; 000206
  - 1951-1960., 001212
    - Field notes. Field notebook #3: Colorado., 1951; 000474
    - Field notes. Field notebook #4: Colorado., 1951; 000475
    - Field notes. Field notebook #6: Colorado., 1952; 000477
    - Field notes. Field notebook #7: Colorado., 1952; 000478
    - Field notes. Field notebook #misc.: Colorado., 1952; 000480
    - Field notes. Field notebook #1: Colorado., 1955; 000464
    - Field notes. Field notebook #2: Colorado, Wyoming., 1955; 000465
    - Field notes. Field notebook #3: Wyoming., 1955; 000466
    - Field notes. Field notebook #5: Wyoming., 1955; 000468
    - Notebook. Field notebook: Iowa, 1951; 000463
    - Notebook. Field notebook #1: Colorado., 1951; 000472
    - Notebook. Field notebook #2: Colorado., 1951; 000473
    - Notebook. Field notebook #5: Colorado., 1952; 000476
    - Notebook. Field notebook #8: Colorado., 1952; 000479
    - Notebook. Field Notes of KMW (1952 trip with Dunbar), & later guidebooks, sections and maps; New York, 000726
    - Notebook. Field journal and log: Colorado, Wyoming, 1955; 000447
    - Notebook. Field notebook #4: Wyoming, South Dakota., 1955; 000467
    - Notebook. Field notebook #1: South Dakota, Wyoming., 1956; 000278
    - Notebook. Field journal and log: Colorado, Wyoming, South Dakota, North Dakota., 1956; 000448
    - Notebook. Field notebook #2: Wyoming., 1956; 000469
    - Notebook. Field notebook #3: Wyoming, South Dakota., 1956; 000470
    - Notebook. Field notebook #4: South Dakota., 1956; 000471
    - Notebook. Field notebook: South Dakota, Wyoming, North Dakota., 1957; 000279
    - Notebook. Field notebook: South Dakota., 1957; 000280
    - Notebook. Field notebook: South Dakota, Canada, Nebraska., 1959; 000281
    - Notebook. Field notebook: South Dakota, North Dakota., 1959; 000282
    - Notebook. Field journal and log: South Dakota., 1959; 000449
    - Notebook. Field notes: New Jersey., 1960; 000212
    - Papers, notes, correspondence. Correspondence, memo's and notes (2 folders) from K.M. Waage, A.L. McAlester, J.H. Ostrom et al. about paleontology program at Yale, its facilities and personel. 1960-1964, 000713
  - 1961-1970., 001213
    - Field notes. Field journal and log: South Dakota, Wyoming., 1961; 000450
    - Locality information. Field journal and log: South Dakota, Wyoming. 1971; 1974; 1976; 1977, 000455
    - Notebook. Field notebook: South Dakota, Wyoming., 1961; 000283
    - Notebook. Field notebook: South Dakota, North Dakota., 1962; 000284
    - Notebook. Field journal and log: South Dakota, North Dakota., 1962; 000451
    - Notebook. Field notebook: South Dakota., 1964; 000285
    - Notebook. Field journal and log: South Dakota., 1964; 000452
    - Notebook. Field journal and log: South Dakota, Wyoming., 1966; 000453
    - Notebook. Field notebook: South Dakota, Colorado, Wyoming., 1967; 000286
    - Notebook. Field journal and log: South Dakota; Colorado, 1967; 000454
    - Notebook. Field notebook: Colorado, New Mexico., 1968; 000510
  - 1971-1983., 001214
    - Field notes. Field journal and log: South Dakota; Wyoming. 1978; 1981; 1982, 000456
    - Field notes. Field notebook: South Dakota, Wyoming., 1981; 000436
    - Field notes. Field notebook: South Dakota, Wyoming. 1983, 1985, 1988, 000301
    - Notebook. Field notebook for Fox Hills Fm, Lance Creek - Redbird area: Wyoming; South Dakota., 1971; 000177
    - Notebook. field journal and log: South Dakota, Wyoming. 1983; 1985; 1988, 000457
- Correspondence, Series III
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondance, notes & memos.
  - Correspondence., 001215
    - Papers, notes, correspondence. Corespondence pertaining to KMW project on Fox Hills otolith collection (Vorhisia). 1962-1978, 000677
    - Papers, notes, correspondence. Corespondence between F.M. Fryxell and J.V. Howell pertaining to Hayden and Meek localities and unrecognized place names. ca 1962, 000678
    - Papers, notes, correspondence. correspondence (letters) of Karl M. Waage, from about 1947 through about 1986. stored in 2 boxes -- A-L & M-Z., 000958
    - Waage correspondence related to graduate students, 002703
  - Letters, Notes & Memos., 001216
    - Papers, notes, correspondence. notes and letters and reports; Pennsylvanian alumina clays, Clinton Co, Pennsylvania, 1944; 000855
    - Papers, notes, correspondence. Late Cretaceous squid (Coleoidea; teuthoid; Actinosepia) project started by KMW but not completed; list of specimens, lending institutions, letters, reprints, & KMW notes, photos & negatives., 1998; 000735
- Photographs, Series IV
  Photographs, negatives. slides & drawings.
  - Localities. Photographs, slides, & drawings of localities., 001217
    - Photographs & Negatives. about 250 color 35 mm slides; Early Cretaceous "Dakota Grp" stratigraphy, Front Range, Colorado, Wyoming, Black Hills, South Dakota, and other strat. slides; several include shots of K.M.W.; many are originals of photos in publications (IP reprints 5026, 5027, 5061, 5062). Donated by Elizabeth Waage, July 18, 2001. 1951-1956, 000752
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black & White negatives & photos, Dakota Grp stratigraphy, Colorado, Wyoming, some published., 1955; 000724
    - Photographs & Negatives. 4x5 Black & White photos of IP collection storage and work areas for several IP collection and facilities grants. 1960-1970, 000715
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black & white photographs & negatives & color sildes of localities, field work done on Fox Hills in South Dakota & Wyoming. Hickey. 1961-1985, 000743
    - Photographs. Photo and negative of field assistant with bra painted on him; sent to U.S.G.S. when they rejected nude-upper-body photo (also enclosed) for publication in Waage's Bull. 1102, Stratig. and refractory clayrocks of Dakota Grp... Colorado, plate 5; (reprint # IP.R.05027)., 1961; 000718
    - Photographs. color slides taken in 1961 by Leo J. Hickey, with list of slides and their field locations plotted on maps; Fox Hills Fm, S. & N. Dakota, Wyoming: photocopy of LH 1961 field notebook., 000971
  - Specimens. Photographs & Slides of specimens., 001218
    - Drawing. Original drawing by Carl Wester for illustration in "The Late Cretaceous coleoid cephalopod Actinosepia canadensis Whiteaves." YPM Postilla, n. 94., 1965; 000733
    - Photographs & Negatives. 8 x 10 black and white print of YPM 1002, Dunbaria fascipennis Tillyard (partype). Replacement photo for Dunbar and Waage (Historical Geology, 3rd ed.) 8 x 10 black and white print. ca 1960, 000546
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white negatives and prints of Cretaceous ammonites (mostly scaphites) & other inverts & plants & concs. & lith structures; including the Yale and Princeton collections; for Jeletzky & Waage, 1978, Waage, 1968, & Landman & Waage, 1993; some U.S.G.S.; includes types of Meek, Owen, Mikhailov, Geol. Surv. Canada, Acad. Nat. Sci. Phil. black and white negatives and prints. 1960-1990, 000612
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints and negatives of various geological phenomena and fossils used for K.M. Waages historical geology textbook. Black and white prints and negatives. ca 1960, 000620
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white negatives and prints of Cretaceous coleoids(Actinosepia) Black and white negatives and prints, 1965; 000611
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and White negatives & prints of Precambrian Ediacara (Australia) fauna for K.M. Waage's historical geology textbook, 1997; 000676
    - Photographs & Negatives. Photographs and negatives related to paper "Post-glacial fossils from Long Island Sound off West Haven, Connecticut" (YPM Postilla 225)., 1999; 000717
    - Photographs & Negatives. YPM 36058, Placenticeras whitfieldi. mososaur; limpet, 4x5 negative and six 8x10 black and white prints, 000547
    - Suite of ammonites (Scaphitidae and Sphenodiscus) from Fox Hills Fm showing brilliant nacreous color; 1 drawer's worth., 1999; 000720
- Miscellaneous, Series V
  - Biographical Material., 001221
    - Information on portrait (painting) of K.M. Waage painted by R.F. Zallinger; Based on two slides [one of KMW by Leo Hickey, 1961, as Waage's field asst.], 1986; 000722
    - Memorial Service, Mar. 17, 2000 for KMW and statements by N. Landman, C. MacClintock, R.K. Bambach, Jeffrey Waage, Jonathan Waage, Ian Speden. Mem.Serv. for EKW on Nov. 21, 2006; biffle definition, 000725
  - Locality Information., 001219
    - Field notes. locality information & color slides: Wyoming (Lance Creek-Redbird area). 1938 - 1985, 000419
    - Locality information. locality information: Colorado (Rock Creek Area); Utah (Logan Quad)., 1949; 000502
    - Locality information. locality information with maps & color slides: Cretaceous, Iowa., 1951; 000500
    - Locality information. locality information; Colorado; type Greenhorn Fm, 1951; 000503
    - Locality information. Locality descriptions, quad index maps, columnar sections, scaphite species ranges, field work done on Fox Hills & Pierre in South Dakota and North Dakota, 1941-1985. includes gift to Princeton (probably returned to Yale) 1956-1985, 000418
    - Locality information. 1943-1957 archive, documents and locality maps, Early Cretaceous Dakokta Group & Inyan Kara Group, Colorado, Wyoming, South Dakota, 1956; 000870
    - Locality information. Catalog of localities: Cretaceous, Tertiary, Cenozoic, New Jersey; 1957 & 1960 field Guidebooks, 000210
    - Locality information. locality infromation (guidebook & road maps): Cretaceous, New Jersey., 1961; 000501
    - Locality information. Lcality information, Fox Hills Fm, Creighton, South Dakota, 1961; 000734
    - Locality information. Upper Cretaceous Stratigraphy, Paleontology, and Paleoecology of Western Kansas: A Field Conference Guidebook: Kansas., 1965; 000332
    - Locality information. Locality info., Radiocarbon dates (Stuiver), X-ray (Berner), petrographic, Speden, Vesper, USACE, maps, Mailing list; Prospect Beach, West Haven, Connecticut, Holocene. 1968, 1999, 000358
    - Eocene bauxite and clay deposits in northeastern Alabama; final report, loc info, sections, letters, 1943; 000854
  - Miscellaneous., 001222
    - Refs. used for MS of paper on post-glacial concs.; 2 Zip discs of Postilla 225; Connecticut (West Haven, East Haven, Milford); Massachusetts (Cape Cod). 1968, 1999, 000742
  - Specimen Information. Specimen information including catalogs, original labels, & measurements., 001220
    - Survey of Storage for Invertebrate Paleontological Collections, March, 1947, by Karl M. Waage., 000714
    - Measurements of scaphitid ammonoids (Discoscaphites) from Cretaceous Fox Hills Fm., South Dakota; and Prairie Bluff, Owl Creek. 1980 +/-, 000770
    - Specimen info. (Fox Hills Fm Scaphitids); YPM # assign., 1995; 000520
    - Measurements of scaphitid ammonoids from Cretaceous Fox Hills Fm., South Dakota, North Dakota, Wyoming, 1995; 000521
    - Original specimen labels & blue removal cards for Fox Hills mollusks, South Dakota, 1995; 000645
    - Rm. 8 Collection Surveys; 1. Cretaceous unit colls. 2. Mesozoic and Cenozoic coll. num. data. 3. Drawer lists - 1970 survey., 000359